<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Hiiraan Online</title>
        <link>http://www.hiiraan.com</link>
        <description>Welcome to Hiiraan Online, your source of news and information about Somalia</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>© 2018 hiiraan.com</copyright>
        <pubDate>Saturday, 4 Jul 2020 00:10 EDT</pubDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        <image>
            <title>Hiiraan Online</title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com</link>
            <url>http://www.hiiraan.com//holimages3/hiiraan-online.png</url>
            <width>327</width>
            <height>99</height>
            <description>Welcome to Hiiraan Online, your source of news and information about Somalia</description>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Djibouti ramps up efforts to get seafarers stranded by coronavirus off ships                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178925/djibouti_ramps_up_efforts_to_get_seafarers_stranded_by_coronavirus_off_ships.aspx</link>
            <description>LONDON (Reuters) - Djibouti has carried out the first crew change of merchant sailors in its territory and is ready to get home more seafarers who have been stranded by the coronavirus, a senior port official said.</description>
            <pubDate>Saturday, 4 Jul 2020 00:03 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Amnesty calls on Somali authorities to free journalist Abuja                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178924/amnesty_calls_on_somali_authorities_to_free_journalist_abuja.aspx</link>
            <description>Amnesty International is concerned about the continued detention of journalist Mohamed Abdiwahab Nur (Abuja) and the organization is calling on Somalia authorities to immediately and unconditionally release him.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 13:01 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>'He's a bridge builder': Ali Abukar helps newcomers thrive in Saskatoon                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178923/_he_s_a_bridge_builder_ali_abukar_helps_newcomers_thrive_in_saskatoon.aspx</link>
            <description>Ali Abukar has long dreamed of running an organization to help immigrants and refugees. He just never through it would happen so soon.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 09:30 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Turkey trial of Saudi suspects in Khashoggi murder begins in absentia                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178922/turkey_trial_of_saudi_suspects_in_khashoggi_murder_begins_in_absentia.aspx</link>
            <description>The trial in absentia of 20 Saudi suspects accused in the murder of journalist Jamal Khashoggi in 2018,  including two former aides to Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, began in Istanbul Friday.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 09:23 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Somalia military says senior al-Shabab leader surrenders to government forces                                                                                                                                                                                                                               </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178921/somalia_military_says_senior_al_shabab_leader_surrenders_to_government_forces.aspx</link>
            <description>MOGADISHU (Xinhua) -- A senior member of al-Shabab militants on Friday surrendered to the Somali National Army (SNA), a military official confirmed.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 09:15 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Omar Musa Obituary                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178920/omar_musa_obituary.aspx</link>
            <description>Omar was born in Hargeisa, in what was then the British Somaliland Protectorate, to Musa Abdillahi, a nomadic herdsman, and his wife, Fatima Osman. At the age of six, he got his first job, fanning a bank manager in an office with an oversized palm leaf. In 1941, at the age of 16, he left his homeland to seek better opportunities, and he spent the next few years making his way down the coastline of east Africa. He worked the land, earned a wage tending to animals, and generally slept beneath the stars.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 08:22 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title> Canada’s First Muslim Lieutenant Governor Appointed in Alberta                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178919/canada_s_first_muslim_lieutenant_governor_appointed_in_alberta.aspx</link>
            <description>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has named business owner and philanthropist Salma Lakhani as the province of Alberta’s new lieutenant-governor.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 07:28 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PM Djibouti decorates Somali Ambassador with highest insignia of the Republic                                                                                                                                                                                                                               </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178918/pm_djibouti_decorates_somali_ambassador_with_highest_insignia_of_the_republic.aspx</link>
            <description>The new permanent secretary of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation, Mohamed Ali-Nur Haji, received on Thursday the highest class of the Republic’s insignia by the Prime Minister of Djibouti Abdoulkader Kamil Mohamed, on the occasion of bidding farewell to the end of his tenure as Ambassador of the Federal Republic of Somalia to Djibouti.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 07:19 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Turkish Airlines to resume flights to Mogadishu                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178917/turkish_airlines_to_resume_flights_to_mogadishu.aspx</link>
            <description>Mogadishu (HOL) - Turkish Airlines is planning to resume it's flights to key African destinations, including Mogadishu, starting next week, according to an industry insider.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 02:08 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ethiopian Airlines, Africa’s largest carrier, sues Minnesota journalist and his independent newspaper                                                                                                                                                                                                       </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178916/ethiopian_airlines_africa_s_largest_carrier_sues_minnesota_journalist_and_his_independent_newspaper.aspx</link>
            <description>ZeHabesha, a Minnesota-based news outlet that covers Ethiopian issues, was sued by Ethiopian Airlines, the largest airline in Africa. Credit: Photo via ZeHabesha's Facebook page.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 01:27 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>U.S. Border Control seizes 13 tons of hair weaves suspected to be from Chinese internment camps                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178915/u_s_border_control_seizes_13_tons_of_hair_weaves_suspected_to_be_from_chinese_internment_camps.aspx</link>
            <description>In New York, federal authorities seized a shipment of human hair weaves suspected to be taken from and created by Uyghur women detained in a Chinese internment camp. The seizure is related to a rare sanction placed by the United States Customs and Border Protection (CBP) on May 1 on hair products from Hetian Haolin Hair Accessories after they were linked to forced labor.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 01:05 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Oromo Community of MN seeks justice after singer, activist Hachalu Hundessa is killed                                                                                                                                                                                                                       </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178914/oromo_community_of_mn_seeks_justice_after_singer_activist_hachalu_hundessa_is_killed.aspx</link>
            <description>ST PAUL, Minnesota — More than 80 people have been killed in unrest in Ethiopia after a popular singer and activist was shot dead this week. Those numbers were released by the state-run Ethiopian Broadcasting Corporation today, according to the Associated Press.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:35 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The African Union needs to broaden its role in Somalia                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178913/the_african_union_needs_to_broaden_its_role_in_somalia.aspx</link>
            <description>Somalia’s historic one-person-one vote election, scheduled for late 2020, looks set to be postponed. Electoral commission chair Halima Ismail told the country’s federal Parliament on 29 June that the much-anticipated polls could not be carried out in less than 13 months.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:31 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Two killed as soldiers open fire on mourners at Ethiopian singer's funeral                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178912/two_killed_as_soldiers_open_fire_on_mourners_at_ethiopian_singer_s_funeral.aspx</link>
            <description>Two people were shot dead and seven others injured Thursday when soldiers opened fire on mourners seeking to attend the funeral of a popular Ethiopian singer, whose assassination sparked violence that has left more than 90 dead.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:26 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Locusts have hit east Africa hard                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178911/locusts_have_hit_east_africa_hard.aspx</link>
            <description>VAST SWARMS of locusts have swept through Kenya and Ethiopia since January, devastating fields, pastures and livelihoods. Governments have struggled to suppress them. They have continued to breed in their billions, threatening whole economies, which are also being battered by the covid-19 pandemic.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:19 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Eight years after bombing, Somalia reopens national theatre                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178910/eight_years_after_bombing_somalia_reopens_national_theatre.aspx</link>
            <description>MOGADISHU - Eight years after a suicide bomber destroyed the building, Somalia has reopened its imposing national theatre in Mogadishu as a symbol of culture in the heart of a city often defined by violence.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:13 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Family of Isak Aden, who was killed by police in Eagan a year ago, files civil rights suit; protesters want case reopened                                                                                                                                                                                   </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178909/family_of_isak_aden_who_was_killed_by_police_in_eagan_a_year_ago_files_civil_rights_suit_protesters_want_case_reopened.aspx</link>
            <description>For Sumaya Aden, the demand that officials reopen the case of her brother Isak, killed a year ago by police in Eagan, the commemoration of Somali Independence Day and the Black Lives Matter movement all are part of the same struggle for unity and justice.</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jul 2020 00:06 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gambia rules out push for Somaliland recognition                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178908/gambia_rules_out_push_for_somaliland_recognition.aspx</link>
            <description>NAIROBI (HOL) - Gambia will not be championing for Somaliland’s international recognition, the country’s Foreign Affairs Minister has said as China rubbishes a diplomatic deal announced by Taiwan and Somaliland.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 14:45 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Local flights in Somalia to resume July 5-Cabinet                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178907/local_flights_in_somalia_to_resume_july_5_cabinet.aspx</link>
            <description>MOGADISHU (HOL) - Local flights in Somalia will resume on Sunday after two months suspension in response to the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 13:16 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Haile Selassie: Statue of former Ethiopian leader destroyed in London park                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178906/haile_selassie_statue_of_former_ethiopian_leader_destroyed_in_london_park.aspx</link>
            <description>A statue of former Ethiopian leader Haile Selassie has been destroyed in a park in Wimbledon, south-west London.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 11:19 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Death penalty for policeman who killed two civilians in curfew enforcement                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178905/death_penalty_for_policeman_who_killed_two_civilians_in_curfew_enforcement.aspx</link>
            <description>MOGADISHU (HOL) - A police officer who shot dead two people in the pretext of enforcing curfew orders in May has been sentenced to death in Mogadishu.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 09:27 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>13 more political parties registered in Somalia                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178904/13_more_political_parties_registered_in_somalia.aspx</link>
            <description>MOGADISHU (HOL) - Thirteen more political have been cleared on interim basis having met conditions for registration by the registrar of political parties.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 08:54 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>UN urges Somali leaders to chart way forward on 2021 polls                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178903/un_urges_somali_leaders_to_chart_way_forward_on_2021_polls.aspx</link>
            <description>The United Nations office in Somalia has called on the country's leaders to reach consensus on a way forward on holding a universal vote as early as March 2021.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 07:52 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Six hurt in scuffles with security forces at Ethiopian singer's funeral                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178902/six_hurt_in_scuffles_with_security_forces_at_ethiopian_singer_s_funeral.aspx</link>
            <description>ADDIS ABABA (Reuters) - Six people were injured on Thursday in scuffles between Ethiopian security forces and mourners trying to attend the funeral of singer Haacaaluu Hundeessaa, whose killing earlier this week sparked protests that killed more than 80 people, a witness said.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 07:47 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>China 'resolutely opposed' to Taiwan-Somaliland partnership                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178900/china_resolutely_opposed_to_taiwan_somaliland_partnership.aspx</link>
            <description>Mogadishu (HOL) -  The Chinese Embassy in Somalia has expressed its disapproval to Taiwan and Somaliland's decision to strengthen their relations on Monday, reiterating their 'One China' policy.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 05:56 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Support helps lift Madino and her family out of hunger and back into production                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178899/support_helps_lift_madino_and_her_family_out_of_hunger_and_back_into_production.aspx</link>
            <description>FAO delivers agricultural inputs and cash transfers to vulnerable farmers in rural Somalia thanks to funding from the European Union’s humanitarian aid programme.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 01:04 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>81 killed in violence after death of Ethiopian singer                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178898/81_killed_in_violence_after_death_of_ethiopian_singer.aspx</link>
            <description>Two days of protests have left at least 81 people dead in Ethiopia, a police chief said Wednesday, after the murder of a popular singer from the country's largest ethnic group stoked tensions that threaten to derail the country's democratic transition.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 01:01 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Somali immigrants find dream farming land in Wales                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178897/somali_immigrants_find_dream_farming_land_in_wales.aspx</link>
            <description>WELLS (WGME) – Somali immigrants in Maine have found their dream farming land in Wales.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:55 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Vulnerable people across East Africa forcibly evicted during pandemic                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178896/vulnerable_people_across_east_africa_forcibly_evicted_during_pandemic.aspx</link>
            <description>Over 70,000 people, many of whom are internally displaced, were forcibly evicted from their homes in urban areas across East Africa even during the most prevalent months of the Covid-19 pandemic - a new report reveals.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:52 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Finland boosting coronavirus healthcare aid for Iraq, Somalia                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178895/finland_boosting_coronavirus_healthcare_aid_for_iraq_somalia.aspx</link>
            <description>The Finnish Ambassador in Baghdad says there have been few improvements in Iraq's healthcare system since the fall of Saddam Hussein.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:49 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nyanza, Western, new breeding ground for terrorists, survey shows                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178894/nyanza_western_new_breeding_ground_for_terrorists_survey_shows.aspx</link>
            <description>Kisumu, Siaya and Vihiga counties are the new breeding grounds for terrorist groups,  a baseline survey conducted in 10 counties of Western Kenya has revealed.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:39 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Djibouti envoy says stability in Somalia essential for security in Horn of Africa                                                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178893/djibouti_envoy_says_stability_in_somalia_essential_for_security_in_horn_of_africa.aspx</link>
            <description>DUBAI: Djibouti seeks to bring stability to neighboring Somalia as the situation of the country impacts the security of the Horn of Africa, the country’s envoy to Saudi Arabia said on Wednesday.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:34 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Taiwan finds an unexpected new friend in Somaliland – Analysis                                                                                                                                                                                                                                              </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178892/taiwan_finds_an_unexpected_new_friend_in_somaliland_–_analysis.aspx</link>
            <description>COVID-19 seemed to change the narrative around Taiwan: from a nation whose existence is often characterized as standing on the edge of a knife to one that capably and effectively handled the pandemic with fewer than 10 deaths.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:29 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Russian voters agree to let Putin seek 2 more terms                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178891/russian_voters_agree_to_let_putin_seek_2_more_terms.aspx</link>
            <description>MOSCOW (AP) — Russian voters approved changes to the constitution that will allow President Vladimir Putin to potentially hold power until 2036, but the weeklong plebiscite that concluded Wednesday was tarnished by widespread reports of pressure on voters and other irregularities.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:10 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>U.S. regulator, Boeing complete 737 MAX certification test flights                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178890/u_s_regulator_boeing_complete_737_max_certification_test_flights.aspx</link>
            <description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Federal Aviation Administration and Boeing Co (BA.N) have completed certification test flights on the 737 MAX, a key milestone toward the plane’s return to service, the U.S. regulator said on Wednesday.</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 2 Jul 2020 00:04 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Somalia marks 60th independence anniversary                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178889/somalia_marks_60th_independence_anniversary.aspx</link>
            <description>Somalia on Wednesday marked its 60th independence anniversary as its president called on the people to seize the moment to realize the dreams and aspirations of its founding fathers.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 20:15 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Military deployed in Ethiopian capital after more than 80 killed in protests                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178887/more_than_80_dead_in_ethiopian_protests_following_killing_of_singer.aspx</link>
            <description>ADDIS ABABA (Reuters) — The military was deployed in the Ethiopian capital on Wednesday, as armed gangs roamed neighborhoods in a second day of unrest that has claimed more than 80 lives and deepened political divisions in Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed’s political heartland.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 15:16 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title> After years as military base, Somalia's renovated stadium reopens                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178886/after_years_as_military_base_somalia_s_renovated_stadium_reopens.aspx</link>
            <description>Somalia's president on Tuesday officially reopened the country's renovated national stadium, which saw its first football match in 17 years, after serving as a base for Al-Shabaab and later, African Union peacekeeping troops.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:56 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Head of persons with disabilities in Baidoa shot dead by Al-Shabaab                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178885/head_of_persons_with_disabilities_in_baidoa_shot_dead_by_al_shabaab.aspx</link>
            <description>BAIDOA (HOL) - The chairperson of persons with disabilities in Baidoa has been shot dead.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:49 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title> Ethiopia police confirm arrest of leading opposition politician                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178884/ethiopia_police_confirm_arrest_of_leading_opposition_politician.aspx</link>
            <description>Ethiopia has confirmed the arrest of leading opposition politician Jawar Mohammed, a move that risks inflaming ethnic tensions that have led to multiple deaths in the Oromia region this week.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:43 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Outflanked by China in Africa, Taiwan eyes unrecognised Somaliland                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178883/outflanked_by_china_in_africa_taiwan_eyes_unrecognised_somaliland.aspx</link>
            <description>TAIPEI (Reuters) - Taiwan and the breakaway African region of Somaliland will establish representative offices in each other’s capitals, Foreign Minister Joseph Wu said on Wednesday, as a diplomatic tug-of-war escalates with Beijing.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:38 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Examining the impact of COVID-19 on Somalia’s healthcare sector                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178881/examining_the_impact_of_covid_19_on_somalia_s_healthcare_sector.aspx</link>
            <description>Somalia has recorded over 2900 confirmed cases of COVID-19 with 90 deaths, and as the cases continue to rise, the health systems in the country are being rapidly confronted with increasing demand for patient care from COVID-19.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:28 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hachalu Hundessa: 'Fifty killed' in protests over Ethiopian singer's death                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178880/hachalu_hundessa_fifty_killed_in_protests_over_ethiopian_singer_s_death.aspx</link>
            <description>At least 50 people have been killed in Ethiopia after the death of a popular singer sparked huge protests in the Oromia region, a local official has told the BBC.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 08:09 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Somali forces clash in Dhusamareb, five injured                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178879/somali_forces_clash_in_dhusamareb_five_injured.aspx</link>
            <description>DHUSAMAREEB (HOL) - Clashes broke out this afternoon in Dhusamareb between two government forces leading to injury’s of at least five people.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 07:55 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AU Special Representative sends a message of goodwill to Somalia on its 60th Independence anniversary celebration                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178878/au_special_representative_sends_a_message_of_goodwill_to_somalia_on_its_60th_independence_anniversary_celebration.aspx</link>
            <description>The Special Representative of the Chairperson of the African Union Commission (SRCC) for Somalia, Ambassador Francisco Madeira, has congratulated the people and the Government of Somalia on the occasion of the country’s 60th Independence anniversary.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 07:50 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Erratic weather gearing to serve up historic dry spells and flooding                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178877/erratic_weather_gearing_to_serve_up_historic_dry_spells_and_flooding.aspx</link>
            <description>Just when the region thought the worst of the flooding was over, the weatherman is warning of another bout; only this time, some areas will be spared but dealt another devastating blow: extra-ordinarily dry spells.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 05:25 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Taiwan to establish representative office in unrecognised Somaliland                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178875/taiwan_to_establish_representative_office_in_unrecognised_somaliland.aspx</link>
            <description>Taiwan will establish a representative office in the breakaway African region of Somaliland, Foreign Minister Joseph Wu said on Wednesday, amid an escalating diplomatic tug-of-war between Taipei and Beijing.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 04:26 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Minnesota’s Oromo community demands justice after musician and activist Hachalu Hundessa is killed in Ethiopia                                                                                                                                                                                              </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178874/minnesota_s_oromo_community_demands_justice_after_musician_and_activist_hachalu_hundessa_is_killed_in_ethiopia.aspx</link>
            <description>'He is our icon. He is a father figure,' says a protest leader in St. Paul</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 04:05 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Djibouti day honoured with flag raising ceremony in Ottawa                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178873/djibouti_day_honoured_with_flag_raising_ceremony_in_ottawa.aspx</link>
            <description>Ottawa (HOL)  - Djibouti marks the 43rd independence anniversary since the country gained its independence from the French in 1977.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 03:51 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>At least 10 dead as slaying of Ethiopian singer triggers protests                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           </title>
            <link>http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2020/July/178872/at_least_10_dead_as_slaying_of_ethiopian_singer_triggers_protests.aspx</link>
            <description>ADDIS ABABA (Reuters) - At least 10 people died and more than 80 were wounded when the killing of a popular singer triggered blasts and protests in Ethiopia’s capital and the surrounding Oromiya region on Tuesday, police and a doctor said.</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2020 03:45 EDT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>